# Razelle Ann Dela Cruz

# **QA Analyst Team Lead**

# **Contact**

San Rafael, Bulacan, Philippines (+63)917 656 8400

<u>razelleanndelacruz@gmail.com</u> https://radelacruz.github.io/portfolio/

# TECHNICAL SKILLS

- HTML, CSS
- Software Testing Life Cycle
- Software Development Life Cycle
  - Waterfall Model
  - V-shaped Model
  - Agile Model

# Automotive System Testing

- Model Based Design Testing
- Unit Testing of Embedded Software (C/C++)
  - Gray Box Testing
  - Coverage Testing

### • Health Care System Testing

- Functional Testing
- Smoke Testing
- Regression Testing
- Manual Testing and Automated

# (Tosca) Testing

- Defect Retest

### Banking System Testing

- Defect Retest
- System Integration Testing
- User Acceptance Testing

### SOFT SKILLS

- Attention to details
- Quality Control Circle
- Project Management, Project Leader

# Summary

Software Quality Assurance Engineer with more than 10 years of experience in Software Testing and have experience in project management tasks. I experienced working in a very challenging environment with high expectations of project quality and productivity while consistently recognized as an outstanding employee through various awards.

# **Experience**

### SEVEN SEVEN GLOBAL SERVICES INC.

October 2021 - Present

# Job Title: QA Analyst Team Lead (February 2022 – Present)

Perform testing activities for Banking System sto confirm the correctness and functionality of the system.

# Roles and Responsibilities:

# Team Leader (February 2022 - Present)

- Create and send daily and weekly project status reports.
- Ensure good quality and timely delivery of project deliverables.
- Directly communicate and collaborate with developers and business leaders regarding project updates.
- Review and submit team member's payroll
- Participate in daily and weekly meetings
- Create and send tester SDLC documents and other test completion reports.

### Senior Test Analyst (October 2021 – February 2022)

- Test data preparation, setting up of user roles and responsibilities
- Analyze, create detailed test plans and test cases and perform peer review.
- Log and report all issues/defects encountered
- Assist team leader in assigning daily tasks and in creating and sending project status reports.
- Ensure good quality and timely delivery of project deliverables.

### **TOOLS**

- Version Control System: SVN, Git
- Coverage Master WinAMS
- Eclipse IDE
- Microsoft Test Manager (MTM)
- Tricentris TOSCA
- Reports: MS Office, SharePoint, MyWizzard
- HP Application Lifecycle Management (ALM)
- Avalog Platform
- JIRA

### **TRAININGS**

- Basic Tricentis TOSCA Automation Training
- Basic C/C++ Training
- Basic Matlab Design Training
- Quality Control Circle
- Project Leader Training
- Coverage Master WinAMS
- Basic Japanese Language Training

# **CERTIFICATION**

- Tricentis Tosca Automation Specialist Level 1
- Tricentis Tosca Automation Specialist Level 2
- Agila Gantimpala Award
- Tuitt Coding Bootcamp Certification
- Best in Quality (Person in Charge)
- Most Improved DR2 (Technical Reviewer)
- Best Reviewer (Technical Reviewer)

### **EDUCATION**

# Bachelor of Science in Electronics Engineering (BSECE)

Bulacan State University (BulSU) Malolos, Bulacan S.Y. 2006-2011

# THREE MONTHS INTENSIVE TRAINING

Tuitt Coding Bootcamp Metro Manila, PH November 2018 – February 2019

#### ACCENTURE INC.

June 2019 - October 2021

# Job Title: Test Engineering Team Lead (June 2021 – October 2021)

Perform testing activities for Medicare Enrollment Application and Medical Claims to confirm the correctness and functionality of the system.

# **Roles and Responsibilities:**

### Team Leader (June 2021 – October 2021)

- Provide project estimates, team capacity, and status reports.
- Ensure good quality and timely delivery of project deliverables.
- Directly communicate and collaborate with offshore leaders, onshore leaders, and business leaders.
- Create and send members daily tasks and facilitate daily huddles.
- Review and submit team member's payroll
- Participate in weekly leaders' meetings, deliberations for performance appraisal, monthly and quarterly Gantimpala Award.
- Review and send the whole Test Support team's weekly status report, team capacity, and planned time offset. (7 sub-team).

# Senior Test Analyst/Sub-group Leader (June 2019 – May 2021)

- Analyze, create detailed test plans and test cases and perform peer review. Perform regression testing when functionality testing is complete.
- Assist team leader in providing project estimates, team capacity, and status reports.

# **DENSO TEN SOLUTIONS PHILIPPINES CORPORATION**

January 2012 - August 2018

# Job Title: Software QA Engineer (January 2012 – August 2018)

Perform software testing activities for automotive electronics - Electronic Control Unit (ECU) source code.

### Roles and Responsibilities:

# Project Leader (March 2017 - March 2018)

- In charge of the overall progress monitoring including the productivity and quality of the projects.
- Responsible for checking the testing procedures and working closely with the Audit team to ensure that testing standards are met.

## Sub-group Leader (March 2016 – August 2018)

- Maximize the capabilities, skills, and capacity of the team members while guiding and teaching them.

### Senior Technical Reviewer (August 2014 – August 2018)

 Ensure project quality by reviewing the tester's output and ensuring that all items are correctly inspected.

# Software Tester (January 2012 - May 2017)

 Analyze, create test plan, test cases and executes the Unit Testing.